Xiaoxia Cheng

Montreal, QC, Canada (514) 586-8226 jenniferyao1996@hotmail.COM https://jennifer-portfolio-beta.vercel.app

Summary

Rich experience in developing, implementing and maintaining complex software projects. Now focus on frontend frameworks including Angular 6+, React, Next.js.

Solid knowledge at OOP, design pattern, RESTful api, GraphQL. Experience in automation tests using Karma, jasmine, jest and cypress.

Experience in Git-based Microsoft development environment Azure Devops. Worked in multiple Agile teams.

A good team worker, self-driven, always professional and enthusiastic.

Skills

- 10 Years: c#/.net, Oracle, MS Sql Server
- 4 Years: Typescript, Javascript, CSS, SASS, HTML5, Bootstrap Css, Github,
- 3 Years:React, Mysql, Postman, Bootstrap, Redux, Angular 6+, Ngrs, Mongo
- 1 Year: NGxs, Cypress, jest, Karma, Firestore, Tailwind Css
- Experienced in Next.js and PHP.

Experience

Nov 2021 - July 2022

ADNM.NET, Montreal, Canada - Frontend developer

- Tech stack: Angular 12+, React, Next.js, Bootstrap CSS, SASS, NGXS, Cypress, Karma, Swagger, c#
- Help the team release the new version on time. Add state management (NGXS) to 20% components (Total: 150+)
- Troubleshot bugs or flaws mainly related to asynchronous processing and responsive UI
- Optimize performance cooperating with backend developers
- Contribute to system test and documentation
- Develop new user-specific features

Aug 2014 - Oct 2022

A learner and freelancer

• Take a career break to take care of my family. Take full-time french courses

- Take high quality online courses to systematically learn Javascript and related frontend frameworks
- Work as volunteer to develop an online article repository using PHP, Mysql ,React and Storybook

Oct 2014- July 2018

Yonyou company, Shanghai - Technical Consultant

- Tech Stack: Java, Html, MS project, Geographic Map
- Participate in creating and executing ERP system implement plans
- Work closely with development team and end-users to ensure deliver right CRM product
- Train users and new employees in best practice to utilize ERP to its fullest capacity
- Help accounts well adapt to financial policy changes by configuring reports on BI platform
- Help salespersons increase lead, accelerate orders, manage accounts receivable and commission

Oct 2001 - Sep 2014

CITS company, Shanghai - Senior Software Engineer and Project manager

- Tech stack: Java, c#/.net, Oracle, MS Sql server, Javascript
- Deliver high quality custom softwares for users in multiple industries. Help users to make more efficient production plans, reduce lead time by 10%+, reduce material cost, timely collection production data, manage e-commerce orders and stock, etc.
- Design and write unit tests, integrated tests and system tests.
- Implement softwares in factories and offer on-going support

Sep 1999 - July 2001

Finet.hk company, Shenzhen, China - Database Developer

- Tech Stack: Java, Oracle, Html
- Define database specifications. Grant Roles. Write sql query. Replicate, backup, profile database.

Aug 1996 - July 1999

Gezhouba Group, Yichang, China- Senior Software Engineer and Project manager

 Develop a custom application to manage hydroelectricity project cost using VB and SqlServer

Education

Sep 1992 - July 1996

Nankai university, Tianjin - Bachelor of computer and information

Languages

English, French, Japanese, Mandarin